A Guide to Virginia Imprints 1774-1876
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Virginia Imprints 1774-1876
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
12055
3.5 linear feet
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Scope and Content Information
The collection consists of unpublished lists and bibliographical descriptions (in manuscript, typescript and photocopy) of books printed in Virginia, compiled by John Cook Wyllie and William H. Runge, of the Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library, between 1940 and 1985.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged alphabetically by city of imprint; most city files are sub-arranged chronologically, although some are sub-arranged alphabetically.
Contents List
- Abingdon (Box 1)
- Alexandria, A-E (Box 1)
- Alexandria, F-P (Box 1)
- Alexandria, Q-Z (Box 1)
- Charlottesville, part 1 (Box 1)
- Charlottesville, part 2 (Box 1)
- Fredericksburg (Box 2)
- Harrisonburg (Box 2)
- Lexington (Box 2)
- Lynchburg -1862 (Box 2)
- Lynchburg 1863- (Box 2)
- New Market (Box 3)
- Norfolk (Box 3)
- A check list of Norfolk, Virginia, imprints 1774-1876 by Mercer Garnett McCoy (Thesis, Ph.D., Catholic University, 1954), A bound carbon copy, interleaved with additional material (Box 3)
- Petersburg (Box 3)
- A check list of Richmond, Virginia imprints 1781-1805 with a historical introduction by Katharine Norman Davis (Thesis, M.S., Catholic University, 1956), An unbound typescript carbon copy interleaved with additional materials and with ms. additions and notes (Box 4)
- Richmond 1780-1859 (Box 4)
- A check list of Richmond, Virginia imprints 1806-1820 with a historical introduction by Mary Lou Langhorne (Thesis, Ph.D., Catholic University, 1958), A copy-flow printout from microfilm (Box 4)
- A check list of Richmond, Virginia imprints 1821-1830 by Ann Reane Clary (Thesis, M.S., Catholic University, 1956), An unbound typescript carbon copy (Box 4)
- A check list of Richmond, Virginia imprints 1841-1852 by Bettina F. McKinnell (Thesis, Ph.D., Catholic University, 1956), An unbound typescript carbon copy, interleaved with additional materials (Box 4)
- Richmond 1860 (Box 4)
- Richmond, A-O 1861 (Box 5)
- Richmond, P-Z 1861 (Box 5)
- Richmond, A-C 1862 (Box 5)
- Richmond, C-Z 1862 (Box 5)
- Richmond 1863-1865 (Box 5)
- A check list of Richmond, Virginia imprints 1866-1870 with a historical introduction by Jean Marie Swartz (Thesis, M.S., Catholic University, 1955), An unbound photocopy of typescript (Box 5)
- Williamsburg 1760-1829 (Box 6)
- Winchester 1787-1876 (Box 6)
- Winchester 1788-1875 (Box 6)
- Wytheville (Box 6)
- Miscellaneous: Accomac, Salem, Warrenton (Box 6)